Everybody, I'm John Kiriakou, and
welcome back to another episode of Deep
Focus Q&A.
My favorite part of the show. But, as
always, before we get started, I want to
thank you, thank you, thank you for your
confidence in the show, for subscribing,
for liking, for sharing, telling your
friends and family, and making your
comments, and please keep them coming.
So, today we've got a whole new set of
questions. I'm going to start with Jason
Walton. Jason says, "Hey John, huge fan
of your media, and very thankful as an
American for the patriot you are. Thank
you."
In your own opinion, how likely is it
that Israel uses a nuclear weapon, and
would that be the final straw where the
US government grows a backbone and goes
against them? Wishing you the best. God
bless."
Man, this is a really tough question. A
couple of weeks ago, and I may have
mentioned this in the last Q&A, maybe I
didn't, I don't recall, but I got
together for dinner with a group of
people that meets every couple of
months. It's four or five professors, a
a newspaper editor, the former NPR
Washington Bureau Chief, and it's like
an old-fashioned salon, where we sit and
talk about the issues of the day. It's
it's all off the record, and and people
can speak freely.
One of the people who attended this last
dinner
has been following these issues for 50
years, and really knows what he's
talking about.
He believes that the Israelis are indeed
prepared to use a nuclear weapon against
Iran.
Um, the Samson
uh policy is real,
and that if the Israelis feel that they
are truly threatened, that the existence
of the state of Israel is threatened,
they will take down everybody else
around them,
beginning with Iran.
But, I'll tell you where he disagrees
with you.
He believes
that Israel would use a nuclear weapon
with the support of the United States.
He said that his analysis is that Donald
Trump views nuclear weapons as
the final taboo
in warfare.
And that Trump wants to break that taboo
so that future presidents
have the ability
to use nuclear weapons against our
enemies.
I have chills just even speaking the
words. The United States is the only
country in the history of the planet
that has used a nuclear weapon and we've
done it twice.
So,
I'm deeply concerned
that this is even being discussed. And
perhaps
that's why the two two sides at least
are making noises indicating that they
might be willing to get together to talk
about an off-ramp.
Uh but
for me personally, do I believe that
Israel would use a nuclear weapon? Yeah,
I do.
Yes, I do.
I don't want to believe I my brain can't
wrap itself around the notion that the
United States would support the use of
nuclear weapons.
I think it would be just
a disaster of
historic epic proportions. So, fingers
crossed that cooler heads prevail.
Mark McCars, thank you for the 11.99
euros.
Hey John, I'm a Turk from West Thrace,
Thraki in Greece. I have some questions.
When you were in Athens, did you get to
know anything of the Greek intelligence?
Whether Greek intelligence has concern
about the minorities in West Thrace,
especially in times like the Cyprus war,
the death of Dr. Sadik Ahmet in an
accident. Um also, I think it is an old
rumor or conspiracy theory that Greece
has hidden a prison near its border with
Turkey to arrest West Thracian Turks
that are serving in the military.
Could you imagine that it's like that?
I don't think the Greek government has
any interest in this region except EU
border control and security. When I
travel through mainland Greece, it feels
like the region after Thessaloniki and
Kavala is a no man's land.
The infrastructure is bad and more and
more people are leaving, especially
young people. The relationship between
Greeks and Turks is actually really good
in the region.
You have a lot of friends around the
world. I wonder if you have some Turk
Turks as your friends. Keep up the good
work. That's an easy question. Yes, I
do. I'm very proud to say I do have
Turkish friends, not just here in the
United States, but in Turkey as well.
Thank you for these excellent excellent
questions. So, let me take them one at a
time.
When I was in Athens,
did I know anything about the Greek
intelligence service and whether it had
concerns about minorities in Western
Thrace?
They did not have concerns about
minorities in Western Thrace. You know,
it's it's the politicians
that are the problem between Greece and
Turkey. First of all,
people of of Turkish ethnicity in
Western Thrace
are called Turkish-speaking Greeks by
the Greek government and they're called
ethnic Turks by the Turkish government.
I think they should be called whatever
they want to be called.
Does it really matter to governments
whether you call yourself a Greek
Turkish-speaking Greek or
a minority Turk? Makes no difference to
me. I think you should decide what you
want to be called. But in terms of the
intelligence service, no. Literally
never came up a single time.
Even in times of trouble like the war in
Cyprus, the the standoff over Imia,
the the Western Thracian ethnic Turks,
it just never never came up. And I was
at the Greek intelligence service
literally every single day.
You say that there's this old rumor
conspiracy conspiracy theory that Greece
has a hidden prison near its border. Not
in my experience. I think that's really
all it is is a conspiracy theory. Um
certainly no Greek official ever
mentioned it to me or to anybody else at
the American Embassy.
And it wouldn't make any sense. I mean
the the 1967 to 1974 military junta was
such a
such a trauma
to to Greece as a nation. Just the idea
of a secret prison like the military
junta had between 1967 and 74 is just so
anathema, Greek word, anathema to what
Greece is today. I can't imagine such a
thing could possibly exist.
Um
Mainland Greece, buddy, I have to agree
with you.
Thessaloniki
is one of Europe's great cities. Kavala
is a terrific place. Outside of
Thessaloniki and Kavala, especially in
the center of Greece as you move west,
it's a no man's land.
Um it needs to be developed. The
infrastructure is terrible. And you are
exactly right that young people are
leaving. They're going to Germany and
the Netherlands and Belgium, London,
Canada, the US, Australia. Greece is
losing its population, especially of
young educated people to the point where
it is going to eventually threaten the
viability of the country as a legitimate
country.
I agree with you that the relationship
between Greeks and Turks
on a on a person-to-person level, and
especially in Thrace, is very solid. So,
thank you for those excellent questions.
Bugs and Clowns, thank you for the
$4.99. Bugs and Clowns says, "Hi John, I
have two questions. Number one, do you
think there's a chance that Netanyahu is
dead, especially with the AI video that
came out from Israel?" I don't think
he's dead. You know, of course there's a
there's a chance, but I think we would
have we would have heard something.
Donald Trump can't keep his mouth shut.
I think Trump would have let something
slip,
but I do think that Netanyahu is in
hiding. There were rumors that he was in
Germany at the start of the war. There
were rumors that he was hiding in Cyprus
later on, you know, after a couple of
weeks. Um he will give press conferences
that don't appear to be AI. A lot of
them do, but there there have been some
that appear to be legit where he's
simply surrounded by Israeli flags.
That's in a bunker, clearly. But that
bunker could be anywhere on the planet.
I don't believe he's dead, but I believe
he's hiding,
which also says a lot about Benjamin
Netanyahu. Number two,
Bugs and Clown says, "I live in Hawaii.
Should I be worried about Iran targeting
Pearl Harbor? There's lots of panic
surrounding this topic out here. Thank
you for all you do and good luck on your
pardon. Your videos make my day. Thank
you. P.S. Will you ever come to Hawaii?"
Totally, definitely, yes. Especially
when my sister and her husband buy a
condo in Honolulu, which is on the
table.
I know a lot of people in Oahu would
love to hear you talk from you. Oh, that
I would love to do that. You know what?
I hadn't thought of that.
I'm going to talk to my agent. You'd be
surprised how many students here want to
go into intelligence. I do not think
Iran will attack Pearl Harbor. First of
all, they don't have the the ability.
We hear about these Iranian cells. There
are no Iranian cells in the United
States, there never have been. There are
Iranian cells in Canada
and here and there elsewhere around the
world, but especially in places like
Pakistan, India, maybe the Philippines,
not in the United States, and not Pearl
Harbor. Um that would be
a symbolic attack,
and
you know, the Arabs might
want to do a symbolic attack. In Arab
culture, symbolism is very important.
The Iranians, no way. If they want to do
an attack, they're going to they're
going to try to kill as many people as
possible. Not that they're planning to
do that. I don't believe that they are.
I don't believe that there's any Iranian
presence in in Hawaii at all. So, don't
worry. And thanks for the uh
the Thanks for the idea on on a speech
in Oahu. I'm I'm going to have to do
that.
Grim Reaper, thank you for the very
generous $50. Grim Reaper says, "Hey
John, I am a huge fan and hope you get
your pardon and your pension back. Thank
you very much. I have three questions
for you. With your rising popularity,
are you concerned for the safety of you
and your family from bad actors in the
government or powers that be?
What book of yours would you recommend I
read first? What are some things you are
monitoring in geopolitics that aren't
making headlines these days?" Ooh, that
third one's a tough one. Give me a
second to think about it. So, first of
all, thank you very much. With my rising
popularity, which has come like
literally overnight in the last 4 weeks,
um I'm more worried about
I'm more worried about individual crazy
people
for a couple of reasons.
First,
odd as it may sound, I get regular death
threats.
Um I will fill you in on one.
A guy called me at 3:00 in the morning,
obviously drunk, making direct threats
to kill me.
This [__] idiot, excuse my language,
used his own cell phone.
As soon as I woke up, I I keep my ringer
off all the time.
So, it didn't wake me up or anything,
but when I saw the the voicemail, I
listened to the voicemail and I was
like, "Oh, really? Really? Okay." So, I
came downstairs, I went to
binverified.com, have a subscription
there, put the guy's number in, and
boom, it popped right up. His name, his
address, his whole history.
So, I texted him.
And I said,
"Dave, you [__] [__] You have the
balls to call me and threaten my life?
What's your problem?"
I said, "Don't ever do it again, cuz if
you do,
you're going to have to expect it when
you least expect it.
And I hit send.
And he answered and he's like, "Oh my
god, I'm so sorry. I was drunk last
night and I was watching your videos and
I didn't realize what I was doing. I am
so sorry." And I texted him and I said,
"If you're not going to deal with me
next time, you're going to deal with the
FBI. Don't let there be a next time."
He's like, "I'm so sorry. I'm so sorry."
Most people are just nuts.
They'll tell me they'll they'll they'll
write to me and say that, you know, the
CIA planted a chip in their head or the
CIA is communicating with them through a
filling in their tooth, seriously. Or,
you know, the CIA tried to kill them six
times this year. And I'm like, "Buddy,
if the CIA wanted you dead, you'd be in
the ground. They're not going to miss
six times.
It's your imagination." And some people
are so like in my face, I have to say as
calmly as possible,
"I suggest you seek immediate
psychiatric intervention." Which just
pisses them off more.
So,
most of the time I just ignore them.
Sometimes they're so provocative, I I
feel like I have to respond. Um
I'm worried enough about them that I now
wear a bulletproof vest uh under my suit
when I give speeches. I felt that after
Charlie Kirk and
a couple friends, you know, have
expressed concern, I thought that it was
money well spent. It's very thin. It's a
it's a bulletproof and stab proof, you
know, level 3B vest, so I feel confident
wearing it. Um but better safe than
sorry.
I'm not worried about the government in
this administration.
I would be very much worried about the
government if the likes of
Barack Obama and his cronies came back
uh into into power. Yeah, that would
worry me.
And uh what book of mine would I
recommend that you read first? You know,
I I really think for for the full
background, The Reluctant Spy was
probably the best. That was my first
one, but it's out of print, and it's
it's People are charging like $500 for
it on eBay. It's ridiculous. I wish I
had more. I I'd just send them out to
people. I used to give them out for
free.
But, they don't exist anymore.
Um
I think the best book I've ever written
is the second one, Doing Time Like a
Spy.
Uh That one actually won two literary
awards. You might want to check that one
out.
And what are the some of the things that
I'm monitoring monitoring in geopolitics
that aren't making headlines?
There's an ongoing war or a hot war
um between India I'm sorry, between
Pakistan and Afghanistan right now that
is resulting in just enormous
uh civilian casualties that nobody is
paying attention to. Nobody.
That's one. Two, I am very very worried
about what the Trump administration is
going to do in Cuba. Very worried.
Um and I'm I'm worried about the the
re-rise
of the neocons here in the United
States.
I don't think that
I don't think that Marco Rubio is good
for this country. I think that he and
and Lindsey Graham are two peas in a
pod, that they are perfectly happy to
get us into wars all over the world. I
think it's bad for the American people.
I think it's bad for the US economy.
It's bad for our relationships with just
about every other country in the world.
We can't just wantonly invade and and
overthrow countries whose politics we
don't like.
We've gotten ourselves into much trouble
over the years. It's easy to invade a
country. It's easy to overthrow its
leaders and kill them. It's really
really hard
to get out.
And we're just going to see more and
more American dead in these wars. I just
there's no upside to it.
Thank you for those excellent questions.
I want to take a break and bring you a
message from one of our sponsors. What
if one signature from President Trump
could create more American millionaires
than any event in modern history. It's
not fantasy. It's happened before. In
1934, President Franklin Delano
Roosevelt signed an executive order that
revalued gold literally overnight. It
transferred billions of dollars in
wealth with a single stroke of a pen.
President Trump has the same legal
authority and he's been hinting at using
it. Here's why it matters to you.
There's a massive gap between what the
government says it's gold is worth and
what gold actually trades for today.
We're talking a difference of more than
$1 trillion. That gap has to close
eventually. When it does, gold prices
could explode, but only people
positioned beforehand will benefit.
Central banks already see this coming
and they've been buying gold at record
levels for the past 3 years straight.
I've partnered with American Alternative
Assets to release a free report called
the Great Gold Reset. It explains
exactly what's happening and how to
position your retirement before the
window closes. So, go to
johnlovesgold.com
to get your free copy. That is
johnlovesgold.com.
Or, you can call 888- g o l d 053 and
they'll mail one to you.
I'm Dotson. Thank you very much for the
$25.
I'm Dotson says, "Hey John, I have two
questions. I consume a lot of
geopolitical content and it makes me a
bit pessimistic.
Me, too, unfortunately. About saving
money, traveling the world, and the
future of our country. So, do you have
any advice on how to navigate the future
world we're walking into?
Second question is, have you seen any of
Professor Jang's content? Very
interesting stuff. Thank you in advance.
Thank you for your stories and thank you
for being you. I got my fingers crossed
for you to get that pardon. Thank you
very much."
Yeah, this is a tough one.
I am an inveterate world traveler. I got
the travel bug when I was 19 years old
and I haven't been able to quench it
ever since.
I I've been bragging for ages on podcast
that I've been to 72 countries. Day
before yesterday, I went to my 73rd. I
was just 2 and 1/2 hours by train from
Poland, and I thought, "Ah, you know
what? I'm going to go to Poland and see
what they have." And it was a pretty
great place.
This summer, my podcast colleague Ted
Rall and I plan to go with our partners
to
Uzbekistan, Turkmenistan, Tajikistan,
and Kyrgyzstan. Why? Only cuz we've
never been there. His girlfriend speaks
Russian, my girlfriend speaks Farsi, so
we figured they could do the translating
for us, but I'd like to add those four
countries. And I'm going to give a
speech in Vietnam uh on August the the
10th. So, I'm adding a bunch more
countries. With that said, I'm genuinely
worried about it.
For a bunch of reasons. I'm worried
about where this war in Iran is going to
go.
I'm worried if we're going to be sucked
into something that we never expected,
never intended. I don't trust the
Israelis.
Um and what happens if this becomes a
longer-term war?
We have bases in a lot of these
countries. Are we going to start using
those bases? Are we going to commit
ground troops? And if we do, does that
draw other countries in? What's the
response going
to be from the I don't I just don't
trust anything that I'm seeing right
now. I'm genuinely worried about it.
Now, I would say, "Don't not travel.
Continue to travel. Continue to do
whatever you want to do, but
be aware of your surroundings, avoid
crowds, avoid places where Americans
congregate, or more generally Westerners
congregate.
Frankly, I would avoid the Persian Gulf
right now.
Either side of it.
Um I was supposed to go to Dubai every
month for a week for the next 9 months.
That's been put on indefinite hold. The
airspace is closed. Half the time the
airports are closed, not just in Dubai
and Abu Dhabi, but in Manama, Bahrain,
and uh and in Kuwait.
Now, Crown Prince Muhammad bin Salman of
Saudi Arabia is here in Washington this
morning, and he publicly said that he
wants the United States to continue
fighting and to destroy Iran.
So, on the one hand, we're we're hearing
about the president uh engaging with the
Iranians towards some sort of an
off-ramp, and the Saudis saying, "No, we
want you to kill them all."
You know, I know that hope is not a
strategy, but we've got to hope for the
best and continue living our own lives.
Professor Jang, you know, I had never
heard of Professor Jang until about 3
weeks ago. So, I started watching his
his podcast and his content. This guy is
very, very bright, very insightful, and
I would recommend that people check him
out. I think uh he speaks a lot of
truth, and I'm liking I'm liking the
stuff so far.
Thanks for that.
Gandalf the Wise, thank you so much for
the 500 I'm not sure what ARS stands
for. Oh, Argentine uh reals, thank you
so much. Thank you for that. Hey, John,
have you ever been to Argentina? Tell me
a story related to Argentina. Love your
channel.
I spent my second honeymoon in
Argentina. I was there for 3 weeks, and
oh my god, did I fall in love with the
place.
Where do you even begin? I went We
started off in Buenos Aires.
And you know, if you had just dropped me
in the center of Buenos Aires
and said, "Look around you and tell me
where you think you are."
I would have looked around, and I would
have said, "Italy,
maybe France."
It is so European and so cultured.
It's so wonderful. There's so much to
do, so many places to see. So, after a
week in Buenos Aires, we went to um we
went to uh Iguazu in the north on the
tri-border with Brazil and Paraguay.
And the waterfalls there, that was
probably the single most beautiful
natural phenomenon I've ever seen in my
life.
Um I saw a black panther
just walking down the path.
I I
toucans in all the trees. I've never
seen anything like it before. And you
got to watch out for the giant snakes.
But uh
I saw an aardvark.
Where in the world you going to see an
aardvark just walking down the street?
Well, not not a street, but you get my
idea.
Um and then we went to Ushuaia, the
southernmost inhabited place on Earth.
We went in August, which was the dead of
winter.
The sun never came up. But oh my god,
the best seafood I've ever had in my
life. We took a dog sled up, you know,
one of the the Andes, and then we got on
a steamer, and we went to Antarctica.
Huh, it was the craziest trip I've ever
had. But I'll tell you what one of the
highlights was.
The architecture in Buenos Aires is so
stunning
that we were standing outside the
Ministry of Foreign Affairs, my wife and
I,
taking a a picture,
and we were commenting on the
architecture, and this man walked up to
us, a man in a suit, and he said, "Are
you tourists?" And we said, "Yes, we're
on our honeymoon." And we were just
struck at the at the beauty of the
architecture of the Ministry of Foreign
Affairs. And he says, "Ah, yes." He
said, "This building has housed the
Ministry of Foreign Affairs since 1887
or 1888, whatever it was, and it's built
in the, you know, proto-Bauhaus style."
And he gave us this whole like
architectural briefing.
While he's standing there telling us
about the building, people were coming
up to him and saying, "Hello." And
shaking his head. "It's so nice to see
you.
How are you? Nice to see you."
So I said to him, "Excuse me for my
ignorance, but
you're obviously somebody.
Who are you? And he said, "Oh, huh." He
says, "I'm the Minister of Foreign
Affairs. I went out to lunch, I saw you
take the picture, and I thought, they
must be tourists. So, I came over to say
hello." What other country in the world
is that going to happen in?
He could not have been any friendlier.
He gave us a true architecture lesson on
this gorgeous building.
And that was just emblematic of of how
lovely the Argentine people are. And
besides all that,
it's some of the best food in the world.
I mean, the beef is legendary. The
literally the first thing we did
before we even checked into the hotel,
we went to a to a steakhouse.
I'll warn you in advance, they eat
literally everything.
Every part of the cow. I didn't, I
couldn't, but oh my god, the quality of
the food there, it's ridiculous. And
then we did the tourist thing, and we
went to see a uh uh um
Evita in in one of the theaters. Uh and
then we went to see uh
Zorba the Greek in Spanish. I couldn't
understand a single word, but the music
was all Greek, written by Mikis
Theodorakis, my favorite composer. And
you know, I just have to say, even
though my marriage didn't last, my
beautiful memories of Argentina
certainly did.
G Rod,
thank you for the 20 bucks, G Rod. G Rod
says, "Hi John, I hope you're doing
well. Do you have any tips on protecting
yourself from targeting by proxy,
documenting surveillance, and
pinpointing who might be behind your
surveillance? Also, best wishes on your
pardon and pension." Um yeah, I do. I
wrote a book back in 2017
called um The CIA Insider's Guide to
Surveillance and Surveillance Detection.
And I get into some of these these tech
issues. I would also recommend you check
out a website called ivycyber.com,
i v y c y b e r dot com. Uh it's created
by a friend of mine, Shawn uh, O'Brien.
Shawn is a professor of of cyber law at
Yale University Law School, and he's the
founder of the Yale Privacy Lab.
He can walk you through all this stuff
step by step by step.
Uh,
I think it's important to know that on
kind of a broad scale, we're all under
surveillance.
You know, certainly electronically.
Actually, Shawn just sent me a phone. I
just got it yesterday. It's a It's just
a run-of-the-mill Galaxy,
you know, Samsung Galaxy. You can get
them in any store. They're at Target.
They're at Walmart. They're everywhere.
But, he loaded it with some software
that he wrote called Privacy Safe. So, I
can take it overseas,
and
it encrypts literally everything. It's
got a kill button. So, if I get stopped
by
I guess ISIS in the airports now as of
today, or we're stopped by anybody else,
or stopped by a hostile intelligence
service, or stopped by the FBI, or
whatever,
I mean, this thing is as good as a as a
paperweight. They're not getting
anything from it. So, check out
ivycipher.com. And my book, I think it's
I'm pretty sure it's still in print. You
know what? Even if it's not, it's it's
going into reprint with a forward by
Tucker Carlson in the next month or so.
So, thanks for that question.
Dumplino's Bricks, thank you for the
five bucks.
Dumplino's says, "Hey John, hope you're
having a good day. I wanted to ask
uh, what you know, or your opinions on
MACV SOG during the Vietnam War, and
have you met anyone associated with
them? I love studying the Vietnam War,
and specifically special forces. Love
your videos, and thanks for everything."
You know, MACV SOG was one of those
controversial
organizations.
There were so many of them during the
Vietnam War. Um, were they CIA?
Probably.
I can tell you that when I was at the
CIA,
um,
there were some
celebrations
of the various CIA components that were
active during the Vietnam War.
I do not recall MACV-SOG being one of
them.
Um and I wondered
at the time if that was because maybe
that was something that we wanted to
forget.
I don't know.
There there was a lot of bad juju coming
out of CIA activities in uh in Vietnam.
Like a lot of heroin coming in.
So, I I don't know, to tell you the
truth. I've never met anyone associated
with them.
And uh
honestly, I don't even know if they're
the good guys or the bad guys.
I would like to bring you a message from
our second uh generous sponsor.
If there is one thing we've learned over
the last few years, it is that access to
medication can change quickly depending
on politics, regulation, and corporate
influence. That is why it's important to
have a pharmacy that focuses on access
and transparency, not bureaucracy.
This is the reason why people are
turning to All Family Pharmacy. Instead
of scheduling doctor visits, sitting in
waiting rooms, and dealing with
insurance approvals, the entire process
is handled online. You choose the
medications that you need on their
website, you fill out a short medical
form, and a licensed doctor reviews your
request. If it's appropriate, they will
provide the prescription. Then your
order ships directly to your door.
It is a simple way to keep essential
medications on hand like antibiotics,
antivirals,
Tamiflu, ivermectin, mebendazole, NAD+,
and more than 400 other prescription
medications that people rely on every
single day.
Prepare now before you need it in the
future. Visit allfamilypharmacy.com/john
and use promo code john10, john and the
number 10, to save 10% on your next
order.
Cballer,
thank you for the very generous $50.
Cballer says, "Hi John, you've said many
times that you were willing to work for
the CIA and put your life on the line
because you truly truly believe that we,
the US, were the good guys. Do you still
believe we're the good guys?
Other than perhaps some small countries
like the Nordics, are there any good
guys left in the international
community?
You know what? Let's just call a spade a
spade here.
Uh no, I don't believe that we're the
good guys. I believe that we believe
we're the good guys.
I believe that our politicians believe
we're the good guys because they have
that simple black and white view of the
world.
But after what I saw at the CIA, a
torture program, a secret prison
program, an international rendition,
that's kidnapping program,
no.
I don't believe we're the good guys.
When we just wantonly overthrow
governments,
we're not the good guys. When we support
a genocide against civilians in Gaza,
we're not the good guys.
When we wantonly
just snatch the presidents of foreign
countries and then
offhandedly mention that a neighboring
country is next, we're coming for you
next, we're not the good guys.
And then your second question, other
than some small countries like the
Nordics, are there any good guys?
There might be a couple.
I think Greece is one of the good guys,
kind of. I think it's kind of slipping
away from the good guy position by
allying itself with Israel for money.
Um
I I can tell you there there are a
handful of countries that I've been to
that I thought, "Wow, they really are
doing it right here."
Um
the Swiss are pretty good.
I went to Uruguay one time. It It's like
paradise down there.
Um the Uruguayans are pretty great.
Chile is pretty great.
You know, the Canadians do their best
but sometimes screw things up. But,
they're pretty good.
I don't know. Are there other good guys?
Not that I can think of off the top of
my head.
Septile, thank you for the 15 Australian
dollars. Hi John, when mentioning good
intelligence agencies, you speak a lot
about the Chinese, Russians, and
Israelis.
What are the Indians like? Are they
skilled? What are their strengths? And
have you ever had to work with them in
your time at the CIA in non-terrorism
stuff? To me, they rarely get mentioned,
but they are a rare case of a superpower
with multiple primary adversaries,
active conflicts with China and
Pakistan, plus balancing friendships
with both the USA and Russia. I don't
know how they do it. You know what? That
is a really good analysis of the Indian
intelligence services.
Very good analysis. I worked with the
Indians
a couple of times, not much, and almost
really incidentally. I will say that I
agree with you. They are very good, but
they're also very preoccupied.
They're preoccupied
with China.
They're preoccupied with Pakistan.
Um
They do try to balance friendships with
the United States and Russia, but that's
done on more of a macro level
between the actual leaderships
of uh the US and India.
Uh the Indians are very, very concerned
about terrorism,
as you would expect them to be.
Um they're concerned about stability in
Sri Lanka. They're concerned about
stability in Bangladesh. They're
concerned about stability in
Afghanistan.
Um and you know, they're always worried
about being sucked into a conflict over
Kashmir
or um into a conflict with Pakistan over
Afghanistan.
It's funny, because Pakistan created the
Taliban,
but the Taliban are allied with India.
It's just one of those weird things that
worked out in a way that nobody expected
it to work out.
Um, so yeah, the Indians are are good,
but they are provincial, they have to
be, and they're worried about
hot wars.
Thanks for that great question.
Well, folks, thank you so much for these
continuing questions. And again, thank
you for liking, subscribing, sharing,
commenting, and all the other stuff that
you do. We're only able to do this
podcast because of you. It means a lot
to me. Thanks again.